<Document>
# Гравитационная сингулярность(синга).

Снигулярность может выдавать бесконечно много радиации, а значит и электроэнергии, без необходимости постоянно за ней следить. Она также может с легкостью заосать всю станцию или покалечит экипаж лучевыми болезнями. Чтобы сформировать сингулярность нужно несколько раз попасть частицами из ускорителя частиц(УЧ) по генератору сингулярности(по ядру). После образования синга начнет излучать большое количество радиации.

## Настройка:

Для правильной работы синги требуется 4 подсистемы:

## Генератор гравитационной сингулярности
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SingularityGenerator"/>
</Box>
Генератор должен быть закреплен в центре защитной зоны, поскольку именно там появится сингулярность.

## Генераторы защитного поля и эмиттеры
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Emitter"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentFieldGenerator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentField"/>
</Box>
Эмиттеры подключаются СВ кабелями и поддерживают поле до тех пор, пока у них есть питание и они включены.
Направьте излучатели на генераторы защитного поля, чтобы подпитать их для образования клетки.
Если подпитано два генератора защитного поля, находящиеся в пределах досягаемости и на одной кардинальной оси, появится защитное поле или клетка сдерживания.
Сдерживающее поле будет отталкивать сингулярность, не давая ей вырваться наружу.
Лазеры-излучатели и защитное поле могут нанести неплохой урон, не прикасайтесь к ним или к их лучам, когда они активны.

## Коллекторы радиации
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RadiationCollector"/>
</Box>
Коллекторы подключаются к ВВ кабелям и при включении вырабатывают энергию при присутствии радиации.

## Ускоритель частиц (УЧ)

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEndCap"/>
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorControlBox" Caption="PA computer"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorFuelChamber"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CableHV"/>
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorPowerBox"/>
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterLeft" Caption="Emitter L"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterCenter" Caption="Emitter C"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterRight" Caption="Emitter R"/>
</Box>

The Particle Accelerator (PA) is a multi-tile structure that launches acclerated particles from its emitters. Its emitters should always face the gravitational singularity generator.
Some stations already have an unfinished PA. To complete, first ensure there is HV cable beneath the PA power box, anchor all parts, then add LV cable to each part.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CableApcStack"/>
</Box>
Then use a screwdriver to screw back the panels.
Scan parts using the PA control computer to check if it's operational. If it shows up as incomplete, examine for what's missing.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorControlBox"/>
</Box>

## Turing on the Gravitational Singularity Engine

[color=#a4885c]Do not[/color] turn the PA on unless all other subsystems are working properly.

Turn power on using the PA control computer. Set strength to an appropiate level.
The higher the output stength is set on PA control computer, the bigger the singularity will be.

The PA will now draw power from the power net and start firing particles at the Gravitational singularity generator.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticlesProjectile" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticlesProjectile"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticlesProjectile" Caption=""/>
</Box>

A singularity will soon appear at the position of the Gravitational singularity generator.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Singularity"/>
</Box>

If no particle is hitting the singularity generator, the singularity will start to slowly decay until it disappear.

## Safety
Singularity emits radiation around it, so always keep a distance. Consider getting radiation shielding gear beforehand. Seek medical attention if experiencing health issues.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitEngineering"/>
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClosetRadiationSuit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterSuitRad"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GeigerCounter"/>
</Box>

A singularity might move around, but the containment field will repel it.
If a singularity escapes its containment field, often referred to as a "singuloose," it will attract and then consume everything in its way.

In such circumstances, there is little to be done other than running in the opposite direction.
</Document>
